const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",i="insurance",a=200,n=120,o=[{id:21,question:"The document that sets out the list of items covered in insurance is a",option:{a:"manifest",b:"bill of lading",c:"policy list",d:"policy specification or form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:257,question:"One of the following is legally used by the insured while the policy is being processed",option:{a:"indemnity form",b:"claim form",c:"cover note",d:"proposal form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:286,question:"The amount given to the insured if he does not want the contract to continue is called",option:{a:"premium",b:"price",c:"consideration",d:"surrender value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:39,question:"The payment made when the insured is  not  entitled to claim under a policy is",option:{a:"voluntary excess",b:"ex-gratia",c:"return premium",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:254,question:"If the insured does not want the contract to continue he receives",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"consideration",c:"premium",d:"commission"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:114,question:"One of the essential features of insurance contract is",option:{a:"Premium",b:"Subrogation",c:"Interest",d:"Disclosure"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:124,question:"Cover note usually run for about",option:{a:"One month",b:"Two days",c:"5 years",d:"3 days"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:292,question:"Speailative risks are",option:{a:"insurable risk",b:"non insurable risk",c:"financial risk",d:"non financial risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:171,question:"The shifting of responsibility of one’s own losses to another is known as ---------- transfer",option:{a:"Fund",b:"Risk",c:"Business",d:"Policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:174,question:"A marine policy that provider cover for the construction of sea vessels is called --------- policy",option:{a:"Building",b:"Mixed",c:"Port",d:"Valued"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:190,question:"When an   insurer agrees   to   replace   irreparably damaged or stolen goods with similar type it is called",option:{a:"Reinstatement",b:"Cash",c:"Repairs",d:"Replacement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:19,question:"A policy that combines cover for many perils as a single policy  to  suit  the  insurance  needs of  an insured is",option:{a:"accident policy",b:"protection policy",c:"paternal policy",d:"packaged policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:106,question:"The amount of money paid periodically by an insured to the insurance company to cover risk is called",option:{a:"Commission",b:"Premium",c:"Cover note",d:"Dividend"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:264,question:"A reminder to the insured who may have forgotten to seek for continuation after his policy expiry date is",option:{a:"notification message",b:"renewal notice",c:"registration notice",d:"agreement notice"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:227,question:"Inter company agreement in which insurers agreed to waive their right against each other for loss is",option:{a:"knock for knock agreement",b:"employers’ liability",c:"tit for tat agreement",d:"salvage agreement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:333,question:"A  trade  group for insurance  companies in  Nigeria is called",option:{a:"Chartered Insurance Institute of Nigeria",b:"National Insurance Commission",c:"Nigerian Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers",d:"Nigerian Insurers Association"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:320,question:"A policy taken to cover several shipments for a sum assured is",option:{a:"floating policy",b:"valued policy",c:"declaration policy",d:"special policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:96,question:"“Hull” in marine policy refers to the",option:{a:"boiler",b:"cost of transporting the goods",c:"goods on board",d:"ship"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:43,question:"To which of the following parties does the principle of utmost good faith apply in a contract of insurance?",option:{a:"The proposer only",b:"The insurer only",c:"The insurer and proposer",d:"The third party and insured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:312,question:"In a life assurance contract, when does  the  principle of insurable interest arise?",option:{a:"At the beginning of the contract",b:"At the time of claim",c:"At the middle of the contract",d:"At the time of payment of premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:270,question:"A method of providing indemnity in the event of loss is",option:{a:"cash payment",b:"professional advice",c:"resolution of policy",d:"resolution of dispute"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:250,question:"The deliberate throwing overboard of part of a cargo without a good intention is called",option:{a:"jettison",b:"barratry",c:"voyaging",d:"overboard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:326,question:"What is the full meaning of “NCRIB” in the insurance industry?",option:{a:"National  Council of  Registered Insurance  Brokers",b:"Nigerian  Council of  Registered Insurance  Brokers",c:"Nigerian Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers",d:"National Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:82,question:"The cause of a loss is known as",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Peril",c:"Hazard",d:"Moral"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:46,question:"The alternative to seeking for surrender value in a life assurance contract is",option:{a:"automatic non - forfeiture",b:"revival condition",c:"paid-up policy",d:"standing order"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:210,question:"Occurrence of an unplanned event is called",option:{a:"hazard",b:"loss",c:"risk",d:"speculation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:209,question:"In insurance, uncertainty of loss means",option:{a:"hazard",b:"risk",c:"accident",d:"earthquake"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:201,question:"Insurance is defined as",option:{a:"risking of loss",b:"pooling of risk",c:"gathering of risk",d:"waiving of risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:109,question:"In the utmost good faith principle, the value of the subject matter should",option:{a:"Be over stated",b:"Understated",c:"Not be stated",d:"Not be overstated nor understated"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:84,question:"A person who has lawful possession of goods belonging to another is known as",option:{a:"Owner",b:"Bailee",c:"Agent",d:"Trustee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:149,question:"The wrongful act willfully committed by either the master or the prejudice of either the owner or crew to the chatterer of the ship is",option:{a:"Barratry",b:"Caveat emptor",c:"Bailee",d:"Jettison"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:134,question:"A house worth N=60,000 insured against fire for N=40,000.  Fire destroyed and cause damage worth N=30,000. On the house under which insurance principle will the owner be entitled to compensation of N=30,000.",option:{a:"Contribution",b:"Subrogation",c:"indemnity",d:"Uberrimae fidei"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:318,question:"The policy that covers  an  insured  employee  against injury  sustained  in  the  course  of  employment  is",option:{a:"professional indemnity",b:"product liability",c:"public liability",d:"employer’s liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:130,question:"One of the following is the duty of the insured in insurance claim process",option:{a:"Late report of the loss",b:"Little idea of the loss size",c:"Quick report of the loss",d:"Hiding fact"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:296,question:"The maximum number of days allowed for a policy holder to pay his renewal premium after it has become due is called",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"conditions",c:"days of grace",d:"days of liberty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:202,question:"In a contract of insurance, a firm statement is usually made by a person known as the",option:{a:"offeror",b:"offeree",c:"insur",d:"client"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:275,question:"A contract which has no legal effect is called",option:{a:"void policy",b:"voidable policy",c:"legal policy",d:"formal policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:330,question:"The amount payable to an insured in the event of fire damage of household items is the",option:{a:"cost of repair",b:"actual cash value",c:"replacement cost",d:"sum insured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:102,question:"Insurable interest means",option:{a:"Interest gained on money in a bank",b:"Interest payable on a loan",c:"Financial interest a person has in something he expects to inherit",d:"The financial interest a person has in something of value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:350,question:"A  temporary  insurance  document  providing  coverage until a permanent policy is issued is",option:{a:"proposal form",b:"cover note",c:"policy document",d:"insurance certificate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:208,question:"An undertaking by the insured that certain things shall be done or not be done or certain things shall be put in place or not in place is called",option:{a:"warranties and representation",b:"utmost good faith and uberrimae fidei",c:"insurable and non-insurable",d:"subrogation and indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:113,question:"A peril is best defined as",option:{a:"Chance of a loss",b:"The occurrence of a loan",c:"The cause of a loss",d:"The result of a loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:70,question:"Which of this is an odd one out?",option:{a:"offer and acceptance",b:"contractual capacity",c:"legality of object",d:"Adhesion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:100,question:"Unlawful breaking and entering into any premises or place of safe keeping is covered under which of these policies?",option:{a:"burglary",b:"business interruption",c:"employers liability",d:"public liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:267,question:"One of this is the consideration paid for insurance contract",option:{a:"fee",b:"cheque",c:"commission",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:294,question:"A risk that has its origin in the activities of an individual and the effects borne by this individual is called",option:{a:"pure risk",b:"particular risk",c:"speculative risk",d:"fundamental risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:302,question:"Which  of  the  following  is  not  a  component  of  an insurance policy?",option:{a:"Signature clause",b:"Particular clause",c:"Recital clause",d:"Operative clause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:53,question:"An insurance principle that requires the insured to be honest and disclose all relevant facts is called",option:{a:"subrogation",b:"utmost good faith",c:"proximate cause",d:"insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:230,question:"one of these is a content of a proposal form",option:{a:"children of the proposer",b:"education of the proposer",c:"occupation of the proposer",d:"educational"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:7,question:"In  classification  of  risks, what is the name given to a risk  where  the  causes  of  events are linked to factors 	that are due to the society we live in?",option:{a:"Dynamic risk",b:"Particular risk",c:"Speculative risk",d:"Fundamental risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:88,question:"A miss statement of fact that is made by the insured or his broker to an underwriter during negotiation is called",option:{a:"annuity",b:"misrepresentation",c:"endorsement",d:"disclosure"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:188,question:"Method of providing indemnity whereby subject matter is being restored to its former position is",option:{a:"Repairs",b:"Cash",c:"Reinstatement",d:"Replacement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:105,question:"Which of the following is not a principle of insurance?",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Compensation",c:"Proximate cause",d:"Insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:207,question:"The legal right that a person must have to enable him or her to insure his or her property is known as",option:{a:"freedom",b:"franchise",c:"insurable interest",d:"Access right"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:165,question:"Life assurance provides dual benefits of savings and ------------ to a policy holder",option:{a:"Acceptance",b:"Consideration",c:"Contribution",d:"Security"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:341,question:"The right of choice of option for method of indemnity is exercised by the",option:{a:"insured",b:"insurance broker",c:"insurance consultant",d:"insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:211,question:"An insurance contract where both parties signed the agreement which involve mutuality of agreement is known as",option:{a:"unilateral contract",b:"multilateral contract",c:"bilateral contract",d:"united contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:126,question:"Uncertainty of loss is known as",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Certainty",c:"Insurance",d:"Hazard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:33,question:"George effected two personal accident policies. The first policy provides N= 25,000.00 cover for loss of limb. The second policy provides N= 30,000.00 cover for loss of limb. What is the total amount that  George  will receive in the event of a valid loss of limb claim?",option:{a:"N= 5,000.00",b:"N= 25,000.00",c:"N= 30,000.00",d:"N= 55,000.00"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:87,question:"The principle of insurance which states that the insure should be truthful and disclose all material fact is",option:{a:"subrogation",b:"utmost good faith",c:"indemnity",d:"insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:58,question:"In insurance contract the insured is the",option:{a:"offeror",b:"offeree",c:"Actuary",d:"Ofree"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:198,question:"A payment made by insurer as a form of sympathy to maintain goodwill is",option:{a:"Compensation payment",b:"Contract payment",c:"Charity payment",d:"Ex - gratia payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:49,question:"Which of  the  following  risks  are  covered  under engineering insurance?",option:{a:"Material damage and liability cover",b:"Boiler and special perils cover",c:"Computer and explosion cover",d:"Property damage and business interruption cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:213,question:"Insurance is a contract that is based on",option:{a:"possibility",b:"probability",c:"positivity",d:"negativity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:112,question:"Hazard that deals with the human habits and character that arises from human attitude and the conduct of people is called",option:{a:"physical",b:"Moral",c:"Static",d:"Dynamic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:76,question:"The following are insurable except",option:{a:"Marine",b:"Goods",c:"Gambling",d:"Accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:137,question:"The sum paid for transporting the goods or for the hire of a ship is called",option:{a:"Marine cargo",b:"Freight insurance",c:"Hull insurance",d:"Risk insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:168,question:"A place where the business of insurance is transacted is called a/an",option:{a:"Insurance market",b:"Brokerage firm",c:"Insurance house",d:"Insurance conference room"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:217,question:"Indemnity is not applicable in",option:{a:"assurance contract",b:"insurance contract",c:"insurance terms",d:"insurance content"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:349,question:"Which of the following factors limits indemnity?",option:{a:"Cession",b:"Re - insurance",c:"Excess",d:"Co - insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:228,question:"Contribution will only arise when",option:{a:"two or more parties disagree",b:"two or more parties are promisor",c:"two or more policies of indemnity exist",d:"one policy of indemnity exist"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:309,question:"A new Nissan car valued at N= 350,000 was used to replace a Peugeot car with a sum insured N= 250.000 in private policy. The Peugeot car enjoys a 25% no claim discount. If the rate of premium is 11% and the no claim discount is transferred to the  new vehicle, what  would be the premium for the new Nissan car?",option:{a:"N= 20,625",b:"N= 27,500",c:"N= 28,875",d:"N= 38,500"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:121,question:"Insurance is necessary because of the need to",option:{a:"Pool resources together",b:"Meet uncertainties in future",c:"Make profit",d:"Lend money to individual"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:317,question:"A clause in an insurance policy that makes a claim jointly payable to the policyholder and the third party is",option:{a:"claim clause",b:"mortgagee clause",c:"mortgage clause",d:"joint liability clause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:120,question:"An application form which is filled by anyone taking out an insurance policy is called",option:{a:"A policy form",b:"A claim form",c:"A proposal form",d:"Proximate cause form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:37,question:"Which  of the following activities is  not a  function of the  Chartered  Insurance  Institute  of  Nigeria?",option:{a:"Setting a standard for members",b:"Promoting Professional growth",c:"Promoting the interest of insurers",d:"Specifying professional qualification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:92,question:"Another name for business interruption insurance is",option:{a:"property insurance",b:"consequential loss",c:"credit insurance",d:"excess loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:63,question:"The evidence of the contractual agreement between the insured and insurer is",option:{a:"policy",b:"proposal form",c:"insurance certificate",d:"cover note"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:89,question:"Indemnity is provided through the following media except",option:{a:"cash",b:"commission",c:"reinstatement",d:"repair"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:143,question:"The clauses in the policy which make alterations or additions to the information stated in the policy is known as",option:{a:"correction",b:"Modification",c:"Change",d:"Endorsement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:48,question:"A <em>revival clause</em> in a life policy will allow an insured to revive a policy that lapsed on account of nonpayment of premium, provided the insured",option:{a:"can prove he is sick at the time",b:"cannot fall sick after the policy",c:"can prove he is in good health",d:"can recover from the ill health"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:123,question:"Risk whose cause is beyond human control is",option:{a:"Fundamental",b:"Speculative",c:"Particular",d:"Static"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:327,question:"Which of the following is not a function of an insurance underwriter?",option:{a:"Determining rates and coverage for the risk",b:"Deciding whether to take the risk",c:"Looking for an insurer to take the risk",d:"Deciding whether to reject the risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:8,question:"The evidence of the insurance contract is",option:{a:"proposal form",b:"policy",c:"schedule",d:"endorsement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:20,question:"A residential building built beside a petrol filling station is described as a",option:{a:"risk",b:"hazard",c:"peril",d:"liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:155,question:"------------ is the protection which the insured buys for his risk",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Compensation",c:"Cover",d:"Subrogation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:145,question:"Factor that causes an exposure to injury, loss or damage is",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Hazard",c:"Peril",d:"Accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:238,question:"Situation that are not included in the policy are usually referred to as",option:{a:"condition",b:"exception",c:"preamble",d:"operative clause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:50,question:"Which of the following is not a function of an insurance broker?",option:{a:"Assisting clients in paying premium",b:"Maintaining proper records of claims",c:"Assisting clients in connecting to insurers",d:"Assisting clients in effecting uninsured loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:203,question:"The premium paid by the insured to the insurance company is",option:{a:"capital",b:"commission",c:"common fund",d:"consideration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:129,question:"The  payment  made  by  underwriter  as  a  form  of  	kindness  without  admission  of  liability  so  as  to maintain goodwill is known as ------------",option:{a:"Kindness payment",b:"Ex-gratia payment",c:"Favour payment",d:"Claim"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:293,question:"The form of risk that can easily be calculated and estimated is known as",option:{a:"non insurable risk",b:"non-financial risk",c:"speculative risk",d:"insurable risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:158,question:"The cause of a loss is known as",option:{a:"Peril",b:"Hazard",c:"Loss",d:"Risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:178,question:"Indemnity is provided through the following media except",option:{a:"Cash",b:"Commission",c:"Reinstatement",d:"Repair"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:331,question:"A motorist travelling from Ghana to Nigeria would be required to obtain one of the following types of motor insurance cover",option:{a:"green card",b:"brown card",c:"yellow card",d:"purple card"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:111,question:"Which of the following is a temporary document given to the insured in an insurance contract?",option:{a:"Cover note",b:"Subrogation",c:"Policy document",d:"Reinsurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:199,question:"The policy that provides protection for goods or cargoes and ships against the perils of the sea is",option:{a:"Fire",b:"Marine",c:"Aviation",d:"Credit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:156,question:"A temporary certificate to show that a cover is in existence is called",option:{a:"Policy",b:"Certificate",c:"Cover note",d:"Claim slip"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:225,question:"The process of evaluating and minimizing risk is",option:{a:"risk management",b:"risk certainty",c:"risk insurance",d:"risk re-grouping"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:119,question:"Which of the following is not a principle of insurance",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Insurable risk",c:"Subrogation",d:"Insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:337,question:"The  document issued by  the  insurer when there is a change in the particulars of a risk insured is",option:{a:"endorsement",b:"certificate",c:"voucher",d:"policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:347,question:"Which of the following is a duty of an insured in an insurance contract?",option:{a:"Concealment of facts",b:"Exposure of facts",c:"Disclosure of facts",d:"Acceptance of facts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:273,question:"A residential building built beside a petrol filling station is described as a",option:{a:"risk",b:"hazard",c:"peril",d:"liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:290,question:"Marine insurance policy which covers all the ship or vessels belonging to one owner is",option:{a:"flect policy",b:"mixed policy",c:"value policy",d:"fixed policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:67,question:"Insurance contract is between",option:{a:"Broker and Agent",b:"Insured and Insurer",c:"Insurer  and Agent",d:"Insured and Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:324,question:"Insurance is described as a risk",option:{a:"avoidance mechanism",b:"regulating mechanism",c:"transfer mechanism",d:"assessment mechanism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:47,question:"Which of the following is a risk covered in endowment assurance?",option:{a:"Permanent disability",b:"Bodily injury",c:"Temporary disability",d:"Death cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:164,question:"Change for the transportation of goods by water is called",option:{a:"Bill",b:"Ticket",c:"Freight",d:"Consideration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:214,question:"Assurance is a contract that is based on",option:{a:"negativity",b:"possibility",c:"positivity",d:"probability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:99,question:"A policy designed to protect individuals against negligence while carrying out their daily activities is called",option:{a:"business interruption",b:"employers liability",c:"engineering",d:"professional indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:261,question:"The settlement of disagreement between the insured and the insurer is called",option:{a:"litigation",b:"arbitration",c:"negotiation",d:"compromising"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:17,question:"How much premium will the insurer charge?",option:{a:"N= 3,750",b:"N= 13,750",c:"N= 17,500",d:"N= 31,250"},section:"XYC Industries Limited proposed a fire risk to Adequate Insurance Plc. on a total sum insured of N= 5,000,000.00. The risk was accepted on a premium rate of 0.35%. After survey, the insurer charged a rate of 0.275%.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:315,question:"Which  of  the  following  would  not  give  cause  for subrogation right?",option:{a:"Benefit",b:"Contract",c:"Statute",d:"Salvage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:224,question:"Risk that affect the society and whose causes are beyond human control is",option:{a:"particular risk",b:"pure risk",c:"fundamental risk",d:"static risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:304,question:"In which of the following classes of insurance is no <em>claim discount</em> applicable?",option:{a:"Money insurance",b:"Marine insurance",c:"Motor insurance",d:"Aviation insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:15,question:"Which of the following is not a benefit covered under a personal accident policy?",option:{a:"Death",b:"Temporary disablement",c:"Loss of baggage",d:"Medical expenses"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:11,question:"Which of the following is not a feature of insurable interest?",option:{a:"Loss suffered",b:"subject matter",c:"Legal relationship",d:"Financial value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:97,question:"A formal document containing the condition of the insurance contract is called",option:{a:"agreement",b:"contract form",c:"contract slip",d:"policy document"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:179,question:"The policy that covers loss of cash while in transit or at home is --------------- insurance",option:{a:"Burglary",b:"Business interruption",c:"Credit",d:"Money"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:271,question:"One of the information contained in a renewal notice is the",option:{a:"previous losses",b:"location of the risk",c:"occupation of the insured",d:"sum insured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"}],t={message:e,subject:i,status:200,total:120,data:o};export{o as data,t as default,e as message,a as status,i as subject,n as total};
